Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpurohit, I am the founder of Family First Financial
Services, I have done MBA Finance and have been working in the corporate sector for 14 years and
today I am presenting to you, if you
want a great product in high risk high return, where you get the return of investment for 100 years,
get tax benefits, you will not be taxed 125% in long term capital gains tax,
get the benefit of insurance cover, you can do systematic withdrawal like mutual funds, you
can also do partial withdrawal if you want, you can invest in many different funds, you
can invest in equity funds, if you
want to switch from one fund to another, you can do that too, many good features
have been given in it, so watch this video completely, if you like the video, then definitely subscribe to my YouTube channel Anil Rajpurohit FFFS,
in the beginning, its special point is SWP which is the main feature with systematic
withdrawal, along with that I want to explain
to you in normal features in full detail till the end of the video Let's assume a 20-year-old person is
purchasing this policy where he will pay a premium of Rs 2 lakh for 7 years and let's assume
that the fund in which he invests
gets a growth of 12%. So how can he do systematic withdrawal? Here, if
a premium of ₹ lakh is taken, the return you get on premium up to ₹ lakh
is tax free. If there is a 10 times insurance cover in it, then here there
is an insurance cover of 20 lakhs anyway. Whatever charges you incur, they will also be refunded to you. Here
you can see the fund value and the death benefit column. Let's assume that the customer
starts doing systematic withdrawal after 10 years, that is, from 11 years onwards,
and the systematic withdrawal he is doing at 7% and he
has been doing it for 11 years. The fund value is being withdrawn at 7%. The fund value will be yours
and you will see that after 11 years ₹ 287 has come in his account which is
the cumulative benefit under systematic withdrawal in the first year, which means
he withdrew a total of 222000. In 12 years, 26000 will come out, totaling
8000. In the 13th year, you will see that he has made a systematic withdrawal of ₹ 111000.
Total withdrawal has become ₹ lakh in 3 years. In this way, your
amount will keep increasing little by little every year. Suppose when he turns 60,
then his annual withdrawal will also be around ₹ lakh, that is,
every year his systematic withdrawal will also be 5 lakh. In total, he would have withdrawn more than one crore by the age of 60.
Even then, he will have 55 lakh lying with him as of today,
which will grow as per the market returns. If the return is 15 lakh instead of 12 lakh, then the amount will increase by
15 lakh. But if we look at the 15% return, then we will grow it. In this way, we can also do systematic withdrawal here.
The money that we are withdrawing, ₹ 1 lakh or ₹ 6 lakh,
is completely tax free because it had insurance cover. In this way, according to NEET,
the customer can do systematic withdrawal and
avail tax free benefit. On investing up to ₹ 1 lakh,
the return on it is tax free. And if I present one or two more examples to you,
then let us see an example of ₹ 1 lakh here, where the customer case
is for 28 years, then this customer has paid one lakh and we are assuming that he
will get a return of 12%. So here you can see how you
will have the amount of systematic withdrawal, how much you would have withdrawn till a particular year
and how much balance will be available with you even at that time, which
will keep getting invested in the market. So if you want to go with an investment of lakhs of rupees, then
you can purchase these policies even with an investment of lakhs of rupees. If
I explain it in a graphical presentation, suppose you are investing in lakhs of rupees,
then how much partial withdrawal or systematic withdrawal
will start for you till the age of 43, how much will start for you till the age of 63,
how much will it be till the age of 68, how much money you would have withdrawn till then, you
will see that here, apart from this, you can see here how much balance will remain at different times,
so you get to see at one place how you
can make better use of this plan by systematic withdrawal with tax free income
because if you invest in other investments, then long term capital
gain tax is levied up to 125% and if you invest in debt fund, then tax can be levied up to 20%
or in whichever slab of your income, even if you are in the slab of 30%
If you have invested in day fund, then you
can be taxed even that much percentage, but here, whatever returns
are generated on investing up to ₹ lakh will be tax free. As I told you,
you can do systematic withdrawal, where I took Ajman at 12 per cent. Now you must be thinking
that here in Ajman, I have told you at 12 per cent, what actual returns are you getting.
Here you get a lot of funds to invest, where if you
want to invest in equity fund, you will get a lot of equity funds, if you want to
invest in balance fund, you can do that, that is, on the safe side, if
you want to invest in debt fund, you can do that. Let us assume that you see,
one year, two years, 3 years, 4 years, 5 years and since the inception of this fund, the returns
will be shown here that from 2009 to 2011, 2015, since the launch of this fund, what
returns are you getting in this, for example, if we see the returns of one year, then Therefore, the one-year return of Value Enhancer Fund
is more than 50 per cent. It has a tax-free return of 50 per cent.
Its return from inception is also around 15 per cent. This
fund was launched in July 2018. For example, look at other funds where the return is 16 per cent.
India Growth Fund has been launched in 2019. India
is growing very well right now. You must have seen that the stock market is also growing very well. So,
this is how investment is made in Indian companies. Here, you see, its
inception date is in June 2017.
An investment of Rs 6573 million has been made in it. Its benchmark is Nifty 100.
The current NAV is running at ₹ 100. Its fund manager is Jitendra Arora ji and he is
managing 25 funds. Edge of Now, out of which 22 are equity funds and three
are balance funds. You can see its graph from 2020 itself, where it started from and
how it has reached at which NAV. It has also come, okay, you can see it here, plus
if you look at the investment here, then
an investment of 98 per cent is being made in equity related securities, about 63 million rupees have been invested in it, there
is also an investment of 2 per cent in the money market, there
is no investment in the dead fund, so at 98 your money is going into equity, that too
according to
the Indian Growth Fund , now
let me tell you about another fund, like the mid cap, the return of mid cap
is also of 40 per cent, Nifty Mid Cap 150 is its benchmark, right now it is getting NV of ₹
Balvinder Singh ji is its fund manager who will manage the fund for you and
you can also see its returns, it started from 2023, at an NV of around ₹ It
was started in November 2023, see in November 2024, the NV has increased to
1387, the returns have been around 40 per cent beyond this also,
if you want to see the AV history, you can also see the NV history here And let
me tell you the portfolio details again, here also 99% of your money
is going into equity, 1% is being invested in money market and
if you see the portfolio details here
, in which financial sectors, about 16% investment is there,
in manufacturing sector, 8.37% investment is there in infrastructure sector,
so your investment is also being made in different sectors, plus
in which companies your investment is being made, you have 2.34% in Sujan Energy, 2.23% in Max Healthcare,
1.79% in BSC Limited, Indian Hotels, FB Fintech, Lupin,
Federal Bank, you can see IDFC First Bank, S Bank, Taj,
Hindustan Petroleum, here you are investing
in so many companies, the fund manager is investing for you in different companies in different sectors
and is giving you good returns, so you can see the complete details
that in which funds your money is going and how much How much percentage is going now
if you look at the returns of balance fund as well, then you are getting
returns of upto 36 per cent in balance fund as well, if you look from inception also, then the return since 2021 is of 12 per cent
, the investment of balance fund multi cap fund is also there,
this fund has also given return in the last one year, even look at the debt fund, the debt fund which
was started on 2 November 2009, which is a safe FD type, has also given a return of 9.28 per cent in it,
the return for the last one year is 10 per cent since 2009, so you can assume it is absolutely safe that
if you look at the income fund, then where does your investment go,
the benchmark is Composite Bond Fund, but look at your investment here,
your entire investment is going towards day fund, going into the instrument
at 5 per cent and the money market is also safe, investment is being made in the money market at 5 per cent
So if the market is going up, invest in equity funds.
If the market is going down, you can be safe. You can do free of cost switching.
You don't have to pay even a rupee. You can switch instantly. You can do it online while sitting at your own
place. You are getting a good tax free return . By investing in different places,
you can do systematic withdrawal or parcel withdrawal
. If you want to close the policy after 5 years, you can do it. If you want
to switch from one fund to another, or if you want to redirect, you can do it. There
is also tax benefit. There is a tax benefit of up to Rs. 1.5 lakh in ATC and
the return on investing up to Rs. 10 lakh in 10D
is tax free. In this plan, you get insurance cover for up to 99 years. This
policy runs for 99 years, that too in ULIP policy, that too under tax free returns.
The investment you are making today and if you are doing systematic withdrawal
or partial withdrawal till the age of 99, Or if you are running it for a long time, you
are getting returns on equity, you can get tax free returns, that too for 99 years.
Under the UL policy, very few companies in the industry
have insurance policies that run for 99 years. If you run this plan for a long time, that is, if you remain loyal
to the company, then you get a loyalty booster. In this plan, you
get wealth booster from the 10th year onwards. After that, every 5 years you get a wealth booster, a
certain percentage. This certain percentage is of the average fund value of the last eight quarters, that is, the last
2 years. A certain percentage of that
is given to you as a loyalty booster. Suppose you were making premium payment for 10 years, then
in the 10th year, 1.50% of your fund value will be added as a loyalty booster
and after that, every 5 years, that is, after 15 years, 2.75% of that
will be added to your fund value. This will happen every 5 years The fund value
can be in crores, on that it will get added at 2.75% every 5 years and this wealth
booster is guaranteed. The company cannot rework it. Partial withdrawal
In this policy, along with systematic withdrawal, you will also
get the option of partial withdrawal. You can do partial withdrawal after 5 years. How much can you do?
Up to 20% of fund value You can do parcel withdrawal in a year. The maximum you
can do is two annual premiums should remain in the policy.
You can withdraw the maximum amount in this policy up to the remaining amount. Total policy is 10 years.
If you do top up in this policy, then you
will do parcel withdrawal of top up also after 5 years. Only after 5 years you will be able to withdraw parcel from the top up amount.
So whenever you do parcel withdrawal for the first time, if you have done top up, then first
your parcel will be withdrawn from the top up and then later in your regular clan. The minimum amount will be from
Rs. 1000. You will have to invest Rs. 1000 as a partial amount.
In this plan, you will get four fixed strategies to invest. Apart from that,
you will also get many different funds. I
have already given you the details of all these funds during fund performance, that which funds
have given what performance in the past. I have already given details about hybrid fund, debt fund, equity funds,
in the policy, you will get the option of switching. If you
have invested in a fixed portfolio, invested in four fixed strategies,
then anyway you will be able to do unlimited switching there. But if you
have invested in a particular fund, like for example, you
have invested in a maximizer fund or have invested in different funds in this way, then
there you can switch from one fund to another four times in a year.
Although most of the customers do not do it even once, but switching should be done.
Whenever the market goes, you should switch your fund to equity. If you want to take high risk,
then definitely switch there. Do it, but if the market goes down sometimes, like
it did during the time of Covid, then you have debt fund as well as income fund,
you should invest there so that if your money goes down, this switching
is free of cost and you can do this sitting at home also through online portal, you
can also do it through your agent. As for the benefit, in death benefit, your insurance cover which is 10
times or 7 times, whichever you select, will be 105% of the total premium paid or the fund
value whichever is higher, you will get that. Talking about maturity benefit,
you will get the fund value in maturity benefit, let's talk about it in the policy.
In the premium payment eligibility criteria, you
are given the option of single pay and limited pay. Suppose if you take a single pay policy, then
a person from zero to 65 years can purchase the policy. If
you are taking the limited pay option and your age is between zero to 52, then you
can take the premium payment between 5 years to 12 years. If your age is 53 years or more,
then you can take the premium payment from 7 years to 12 years. If you
want to purchase a whole life policy, then you can take the premium payment from 7 years to 15 years.
Talking about the policy term, you can take the policy term for whole life
or if you want to take the limited pay option, then there you can take 75 years
minus your entry age. Suppose if you are 75 and your age is 40 years, then make 75 - 40.
You can take a policy term of 35. Talking about the maximum policy term in single pay,
you will get a maximum policy term of 10 years. In limited pay you will get insurance cover 1.25 times or
1.10 times and the good thing is that if your salary is 39 or less then
in single premium also you can get insurance cover upto 10 times. As for the minimum premium then
in limited pay you can purchase this policy with a premium of 1 lakh. If you
purchase single pay policy then you
can purchase the policy with a minimum premium of 2 lakhs. Talking about the entry age then
a person from zero years to 60 years can purchase the policy in limited pay and in single pay you
can purchase this policy even upto the age of 65. Now if you take this Uli policy for a long period of 10 years
then what is the benefit to you, overall what is your expense ratio, like
in mutual fund we talk about what is your total expense ratio but in this
plan your total expense ratio will be less than 1 per if you are purchasing the policy
for long term like Here an example is given that
if you have invested in Maximizer Fund and there are seven years in premium payment and if you
see, suppose you are paying a premium of Rs 3 lakh and the policy term is 30 years, then
your total expense ratio is 1.10. And if the premium
is around Rs 10 lakh, then your expense ratio will be 0.94, that is, the lesser the cost, the
lesser the charges, the higher will be your ED, the higher will be your returns.
So in the long term, it is giving competition to mutual funds as well. Talking about
the charges in this plan, the premium allocation charges in it
will be Rs 5 from the first to the seventh year, Rs 2 in the eighth and ninth year and Rs 1 in the 10th year,
after that there are no premium allocation charges. The good thing
in this plan is that you get refund of premium allocation charges from the 10th year onwards,
that too in every 5-year gap. For example, you If you pay a premium of ₹1 lakh
for the first 7 years at the age of 55, that means around Rs.335000, then
Rs.000 on the 8th and 9th year and then Rs.000 again, so total charges of Rs.0000
are deducted as premium allocation in 10 years, but you will get Rs.40000 back in the 10th year, then you
will get Rs.40000 in the 15th year as well, Rs.40000 in the 20th year as well and Rs.25th year as well.
In this way, if the policy term is up to 100 years, then in every gap of 5 years, ₹440000 will
get added to the fund value as premium allocation. In this policy, FMC
charges will also remain at 1.35 and mortality charges will be on sum at risk, for example,
suppose your insurance is Rs.1 lakh, as soon as your fund value goes above Rs.10 lakh,
mortality charges will become zero. Talking about other benefits and features of the policy,
in this policy you will get You will get the settlement option that when the policy matures, suppose
you do not want to take your XY fixed fund value immediately but
want to take it in the next 5 years in yearly, quarterly or monthly mode through ECS, then you can take it.
In this policy, let us talk about premium redirection. Let us assume that you
have selected any one of the four strategies at the time of inception of the policy.
Now whatever premium you want to pay in future, suppose you have paid the premium for two-three years,
now suppose your fourth premium is coming and you feel that no, I do
not want to invest in this fixed strategy and invest in a particular fund,
suppose I want to invest in a maximizer fund, then
under redirection, this is not called switching, it is called redirection. This
fourth premium of yours, suppose it is ₹ lakh, then you can invest
it completely in the maximizer fund. So in this way you
will get the benefit of redirection as well, plus in this policy you will also get the benefit of top up, minimum top up. Up
You can do top up with ₹ You will also get 1.25 times insurance cover
You will also get increase and decrease in sums If you
had taken insurance cover in the beginning against seven times annual premium and you
want to increase it to 10 times or if you took 10 times and want to make it seven times, then you can do it
Talking about increase and decrease in premium payment, you
can increase the premium payment but cannot decrease it For this, you will
have to inform the company two months in advance Talking about increasing the policy term, you
can also increase the policy term but cannot decrease it If you want to increase the policy term, you can do it Then in this policy, if you want to surrender
after 5 years, you
can surrender it Before this, if you stop, then your policy will go to discontinue fund
and after that, if you want to withdraw money only after 5 years, then you
will be able to withdraw it Talking about loan, because this is a Uli policy, it is a unit insurance policy, it
is a market based policy, so loan It is not available. Talking about income tax benefit,
if you pay premium up to ₹ lakh under section ATC of income tax, you get rebate on it.
You can invest up to ₹ lakh in this policy, then the returns on it
will be tax free under section 101D of income tax. Talking about free look period and grace
period, it will be for 30 days. After the policy comes home,
there is a free look period of 30 days, which if for some reason you
are not satisfied with the policy and want to cancel, you can do so and you
get a grace period of one month at the time of renewal premium. Talking about revival period, if for some reason
you are not able to pay the premium on time, then you have 3 years of time, during which
you can get the policy revived by paying late fees etc. in the policy, if there is a need to get a medical test done, then you
can get that done and get the policy revived again, so finally, if
I surprise this plan, then it is an excellent unit linked insurance plan which The premium payment lasts for up to 99
years. You can pay the premium in single premium, five pay, ten pay, ten pay in this
way according to your requirement. You
can invest in different funds where
you have got returns of up to 50% in a year. You can do switching, from equity to equity,
you can invest in different strategies. You can
take 10 time insurance cover in single pay, which will give tax free income.
You do not have to pay long term capital gains tax on 125% of your fund value on investment of ₹ lakh.
You are also getting insurance cover on maturity over your fund value.
You are also getting tax benefit of ATC, 10% of 10D.
Option of parcel withdrawal is also given. You
can take retirement under this policy systematically, that too
through tax free pension. Technically, you can use it systematically.
You can withdraw certain percentage of fund value as per your requirement. If needed, you
can also take the help of parcel vidal. So if you liked this video and
want to purchase the policy from me then call me on 9094 342 or 3412, consult, compare
and purchase. If you liked the video, on leaving
you will find 3 videos on youtube which will help you in doing the right financial planning on insurance, term plan, mediclaim etc.
Thank you so much, Jai Hind.